Miroslav Tushev

I am a PhD candidate (research assistant) with 4+ years of experience in data analytics seeking a data scientist position. I recently developed and published an unsupervised keyword-assisted topic modeling approach for textual app reviews in the top-1 conference in Software Engineering (ICSE'22). Skilled in Python, predictive modeling, inferential and descriptive statistics, data scraping and visualization, and machine learning.

EXPERIENCE

Louisiana State University, Department of Computer Science and Engineering — Research Assistant

2018 - PRESENT

- Published 10+ scientific papers in top venues in the field of Software Engineering, developing practical solutions for improving software products.
- Helped PI secure 2 NSF grants worth \$210,000 to sponsor our research lab and graduate students for 3 years.
- Developed and published an unsupervised approach for topic modeling of user reviews that outperformed LDA by 95%.
- Programmed a data scraping and code repository analysis tool in C# (10 kLOC) for GitHub projects. Published in 2 papers.
- Applied web data scraping libraries in Python to extract, clean, and organize datasets of mobile app reviews and Tweets for further analysis. Built end-to-end ML models.
- Posed hypotheses, applied statistical analysis, visualized data, and developed machine learning models to gain insights from massive datasets of user feedback.

Louisiana State University, Department of Computer Science and Engineering — *Teaching Assistant*

2018 - 2020

- Designed and conducted an experiment to measure the impact of GitHub as a student collaboration platform.
- Independently supervised classes of 60-100 students (Numerical Methods with MATLAB and Intro to Java programming).
- Led LSU Pre-College Python summer camps for high-achieving K-12 students.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Blog about data science and ML on Medium (miroslavtushev.medium.com).
- Served as a student volunteer for the International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE 2021).
- Maintained the official website and social media accounts of Crowd-Based Requirements Engineering Conference (CrowdRE 2020, 2021).
- Served as a reviewer for the International Conference of Mining Software Repositories (MSR).

PROFILE

Phone
+1 (225) 937-6341
Email
miroslavtushev@gmail.com
Portfolio
github.com/miroslavtushev
Blog
miroslavtushev.medium.com
Personal Webpage

EDUCATION

PhD in Computer Science Louisiana State University 2018 - 2022

miroslavtushev.com

MSc in Computer Science Louisiana State University 2016 - 2018

BSc in Management
The Russian Presidential
Academy of National
Economy and Public
Administration
2009 - 2014

SKILLS

Programming: Python, C#, Java, bash, CSS, JS, C.

Libraries: pandas, numpy, scikit-learn, scipy, spacy, NLTK, gensim, matplotlib, tensorflow.

Data Science: A/B testing, EDA, data scraping, wrangling, visualization, modeling, and interpretation, hypothesis testing, experimental design.

Misc: SQL, git, MS Excel.